EDOUARD JEAN-PHIL KOMBO

LEAD DÉVELOPPEUR CHEZ HEADOO

Summary

I've been initiated to web development at the age of 16, and it quickly became a passion.

Now, after 8 years of professional experience, as a full stack lead developer, I invest myself in many high level requirement professional challenges, and also personal challenges. With what am I used to work? Php >=5.3, Symfony >=2.5, AngularJS, ElasticSearch, Java for android, RabbitMq, Nginx, Github, MemCache, APC, Mysql, VanillaJS, NodeJs, CodeCeption for unit tests.

I also oftenly work with some design patterns like factory and observer, and have created my own principle, the CABIN principle (Concrete Abstraction of Interfaces).

Below, you'll be able to find links about: - Some of my opensource projects on Github (Front, back, windows...) - My android applications on the playstore (Java for android only) - A link to my blog, where I share my knowledge.

If you need to consult my cv: http://vps68191.ovh.net Thank you for reading.

Skills

- PHP
- JavaScript
- MySQL

- Java
- Android SDK
- Linux Server

- Debian
- HTML 5
- CSS3

- Web Design
- Symfony
- Doctrine

- Git
- $\bullet \ \ Codeception$
- PHPUnit

- AngularJs
- Node.js
- Grunt

- CSS
- HTML5
- · Web design

Experience

Headoo Lead développeur

01 / 2014 - Present

Backend Side . Symfony 2.0 to 2.5 company website migration . Good pratices methods used for user roles and ACL . API management system with FOSRestBundle . Use of Doctrine extensions and behaviors . Payment system with the excellent PayumBundle . Choice of LiipImagineBundle for fileSystem management . Dropbox, Facebook, Twitter sdk . Codeception for unit, functional and acceptance tests . ElasticSearch to improve search performance for statistics inside backoffice . Internationalization system, including database with Doctrine behaviors . Bug fixes . Some php scripts hosted on my Github . New development logics with design pattern implementation Server Side (Linux Ubuntu distribution) . Dropbox, FFMPEG, Nginx, ElasticSearch, MEMCACHE installation . Linux user account management . Cluster management with

database replication . ElasticSearch monitoring . Load balancing with LVS . Mail system with ISPConfig . Forever implementation, for running NodeJS applications in background . etc...

Front Side . Development of "Monalisa", an Html5 video application for the first "videoMaton" in France . Monalisa runs only over NodeJS with expressJS server . Two versions of Monalisa (vanillaJS and AngularJS) . Internationalization with AngularJs, plus angularJS SEO issues . Usage of NodeJs with NPM and Bower for front dependencies . Many little javascript scripts, hosted on my Github Low level softwares . Powershell script to send pictures directly from a computer ton an ipad through ftp inside a local wifi network . Windows (xp to 2008) software development for the Monalisa application. (Install our application on all videomaton machines effortlessly) . Mac OSX and Linux softwares in progress Mobile side . Android mobile application development. Take a picture from your mobile with our application, and get it on our digital platform Scalability management . Nginx to handle http requests asynchronously . Nginx microcaching and reverse proxy . MemCache to speed up data access

DATA-GEST Lead développeur

05 / 2012 - 11 / 2013

Backend Side . Rewriting of company home framework with Symfony 2.2 . Implementation of unit testing practice with CodeCeption . Strong implementation of design patterns to handle code scalability . Simple php api development that communicates with Microsoft Navision ERP . Light e-commerce platform development with Symfony 2.2 . Implementation of JMSPaymentBundle to deal with payment gateways . Light home CMS development to easily deploy the same e-commerce website for multiple customers

Front Side . Cookies management . Some little and helpful scripts using XMLHttpRequest $\,$

Server Side . A management of three servers cluster . Mail server management with ISPConfig . Git, Composer installation. A VCS is mandatory for team work. . RabbitMQ installation to communicate between the servers through AMQ protocol Scalability management . Data caching with MemCache . Varnish as reverse proxy . Mysql Cache . Cron system to handle huge database operations on specific time . High performance servers

Management and methodology . Three developers management (two juniors, one confirmed) . Always with agile method . Permanent contact with sales team and customers

ND Interactive Développeur web

12 / 2011 - 04 / 2012

Backend Side . Website developement from A to Z with Symfony 2.0.1 . User and groups management system with FOSUserBundle . User role management with ACL system . Private messaging system . Internationalization (French, english) . Cache management system with APC . Facebook API implementation

Front Side . NodeJS with socket.io to deal with a real time application . Home based chat system . Cookies management . Multiple native JS and jQuery scripts development Server Side . Learning the basics with the system administrator

Scalability management . Very high performance servers . Varnish as reverse proxy . MemCache for datas . Mysql Cache

Management and methodology . Co-working with an integrator and an ux designer . Always with a gile method $\,$

WEBPOPULATION Développeur web

05 / 2011 - 10 / 2011

Backend Side . Training on webpopulation framework, inspired from ZendFramework . Integration of Facebook and youtube api . Paypal, CreditAgricole, Ogone payment gateways implementation . From scratch user role management system . Search with mysql caching and smart pagination . Internationalization (French, english) . Facebook API implementation

Front Side . Multiple native JS and jQuery scripts development Management and methodology . Co-working with a pole of ten developers and integrators . Always with agile method

Deedooz CEO

04 / 2009 - 05 / 2011

Backend Side . Website from scratch with no framework, nor CMS . User management system . Payment management system with Paypal, Moneybooker and ogone gateways . Comment management system . Rating management system . Complaint management system . Account history and billing . Product management system . Custom ACL management system . Internationalization system . Bug fixes

Server Side (Linux Ubuntu distribution) . Shared hosting with security features and mail server ready

Front Side . Html and CSS template integration . Multibrowser testing . Many little native javascript and jQuery scripts

Management and methodology . Always with agile method . One associate, one press officer, and one employee $\,$

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{Travel}}$. Travel throughout France to find funds and create business opportunities

Elsevier

11 / 2007 - 03 / 2009

Web Designer, web développeur

Backend Side . Flash animation development in AS3 for rich media banners (Action Script 3) . Interactive media presentation for books, in AS3 . Little basic php scripts . Bug fixes

Front Side . Template design with Photoshop . Html an CSS template integration . Multibrowser testing

Management and methodology . Always with agile method

Training . Several hours of personal training about php development

Education

Lycée jean-perrin BTS , Electronique

2002 - 2007

Président du club radio interne

Certifications

PHP CLASS A CERTIFICATE (SYMFONY 2.X) 01 / 2015 People Centric France · License: itPiyJGPKRqCCGTCbtDXzyrROVWuXyMgRBp

WEB DESIGN CLASS A CERTIFICATE (HtmL5) 01 / 2015

People Centric France · License: puYFGfbJdaRWXHFcFplmtaVHjMVZvkkKFjp

WEB DESIGN CLASS A CERTIFICATE (Javascript)

01 / 2015

People Centric · License: LtVQFCMQrbIvYdlVvWooBPqVLWSrEGOpaJf/

Languages

• français

anglais